<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Andrés Pérez-Figueroa</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Andrés Pérez-Figueroa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Andrés Pérez-Figueroa</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The paper in which I went from being a reviewer to being one of the co-authors</title>
      <link>/post/the-paper-in-which-i-went-from-being-a-reviewer-to-being-one-of-the-co-authors/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-paper-in-which-i-went-from-being-a-reviewer-to-being-one-of-the-co-authors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last week Marine Biology has published a paper of which I am co-author with . Under the title &lt;a href=&#34;publication/2018.watson/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Morphological and epigenetic variation in mussels from contrasting environments&lt;/a&gt; it is a study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The curious story about this paper is that I was a reviewer in a previous version also in Marine Biology. When reading that manuscript I&amp;rsquo;ve found a wrong sentence that maked an assumption that invalidates most of the subsequent analysis. My surprise was at maximum when I see that statement cited me as personal communication&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not another Impostor Syndrome post: a failed scientist</title>
      <link>/post/not-another-impostor-syndrome-post-a-failed-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/not-another-impostor-syndrome-post-a-failed-scientist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How long you can be a postdoc? 5, 10, 15 years?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say “I’m a fraud”. I don’t believe that. I know well my strengths and my weaknesses. This is not a post about I’m suffering the called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Impostor_syndrome&#34;&gt;impostor syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not. I really failed to become a scientist. More properly, I failed to build an successful academic career in science. I would like to explain the how and why. This is jut for me, to expose my feelings about the current point in my career. However, if this could help you to analyze your goals and, maybe, avoid some of the mistakes I think I made, then I would be greatly satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tldr&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;tl;dr&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I earned my PhD 12 years ago, in 2005. I am currently working as a postdoc for a project where I am not PI. This is my 7th or 8th postdoc (I’ve really lost the account), and like most of them, linked to my &lt;em&gt;alma mater&lt;/em&gt;. My contract expires at the end of 2018. I never earned a research grant (just a couple of fellowships). I cannot apply for most of the fellowships to start an independent PI career as I’m too old (&amp;gt;10 years) and my CV has several deficiencies. And I have virtually no chance of getting a permanent position in the academy. Therefore, I am in a dead end. But I am the only one responsible for this situation. Some bad decisions, together with the bad luck of the conjuncture (the great economic crisis since 2008) and some personal limitations (my partner got a fixed job fairly soon, in 2007) are the causes why I was not able to develop a consistent scientific / academic career. So far I have been surviving from project to project thanks to a series of technical skills. However, these continuous changes of lines of research (none of my own) have also been weighing my already battered possibilities of becoming an IP. Without remorse, I will continue working on different projects while someone continues to have an interest in my limited abilities. However, already with 40 years and a family, I look for alternatives away from academia and science. Of course, I have enjoyed doing what I really like all these years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;my-personal-story-how-i-got-to-this-point&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;My personal story: How I got to this point&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;my-strengths&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My strengths&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;my-weaknesses&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;My weaknesses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;what-i-have-really-done-wrong&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I have really done wrong&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;and-now-what-do-i-do&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And now what do I do?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redesigning the website</title>
      <link>/post/redesigning-the-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/redesigning-the-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve changed the website design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 2 years this site was relying on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Jekyll framework&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mmistakes.github.io/minimal-mistakes/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Minimal Mistakes template&lt;/a&gt;. Recently, I started to dive deeper in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rstudio.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rstudio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rmarkdown&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidyverse.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;tidyverse&lt;/a&gt; ecosystem. Few days ago I discovered in Twitter about the new Yihui Xie&amp;rsquo;s package called &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt; that allows to create static websites using Rmarkdown and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. After a quick read of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Xie&amp;rsquo;s book about this package&lt;/a&gt; I decided to change this website from Markdown+Jekyll to Rmarkdown+Blogdown+Hugo. Of course, the migration is quite easy as this website was almost empty and unchanged for these 2 years. In fact, this decision was boosted by the fact that I was trying to update Jekyll and found some troubles with ruby dependencies. Furthermore, the chapter 3.4 of the Xie&amp;rsquo;s book gave me the idea to avoid relying on having everything installed on the computer: using &lt;a href=&#34;https://travis-ci.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Travis CI&lt;/a&gt; to make the deployment to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; (where the website was already hosted in the repo &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anpefi/anpefi.github.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;anpefi/anpefi.github.io&lt;/a&gt;). Although I already used Travis-CI for some of my programs, I did not use it to do the deployment. I was curious about how it would work and to pass this website to that system would allow me to practice. For this I had to create a new repository (&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/anpefi/anpefi.source&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;anpefi/anpefi-source&lt;/a&gt;) for the sources of the page, which, with each commit in the master, will be built in Travis-CI and the static html deployed in anpefi.github.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how the site looked in the last 2 years:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/posts/old.website.png&#34; alt=&#34;old layout&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic template&lt;/a&gt; for Hugo that I think it looks great for a site like this. What do you think? Leave me your comments below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first impressions about the change from Jekyll to Hugo are very positive, and now it is easier to do everything from one place (Rstudio) and the pages are generated much faster and with a lighter load. The deployment via Travis also has an additional advantage, and that is that I do not depend on having the installation of R or Hugo on a computer. Now I can add content directly from the github website or from the mobile. It seems that the change has been a success. Now I just have to motivate myself to write some posts from time to time, but that&amp;rsquo;s another bussiness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
